<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.2.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2021-04-03T22:32:28+00:00</updated><id>/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Digital Garden | Notes</title><subtitle>A digital garden or public notebook for The Bentway’s Digital and/as Public Space Micro-Residency.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">World Wide Web</title><link href="/world-wide-web" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="World Wide Web" /><published>2021-04-03T22:32:28+00:00</published><updated>2021-04-03T22:32:00+00:00</updated><id>/world-wide-web</id><content type="html" xml:base="/world-wide-web">&lt;p&gt;TBD&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">TBD</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Web Browser</title><link href="/web-browser" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Web Browser" /><published>2021-04-03T22:32:28+00:00</published><updated>2021-04-03T22:32:00+00:00</updated><id>/web-browser</id><content type="html" xml:base="/web-browser">&lt;p&gt;A web browser (commonly referred to as a browser) is a software application for accessing the &lt;a class=&quot;internal-link&quot; href=&quot;/world-wide-web&quot;&gt;World Wide Web&lt;/a&gt;. When a user requests a web page from a particular website, the web browser retrieves the necessary content from a web server and then displays the page on the user’s device.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Web_browser&quot;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Web_browser&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">A web browser (commonly referred to as a browser) is a software application for accessing the [[World Wide Web]]. When a user requests a web page from a particular website, the web browser retrieves the necessary content from a web server and then displays the page on the user’s device. https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Web_browser</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Statement of Intent</title><link href="/statement-of-intent" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Statement of Intent" /><published>2021-04-03T22:32:28+00:00</published><updated>2021-04-03T22:32:00+00:00</updated><id>/statement-of-intent</id><content type="html" xml:base="/statement-of-intent">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;internal-link&quot; href=&quot;/hypha&quot;&gt;Hypha&lt;/a&gt;’s practice is situated across many topics that are present in the theme of &lt;em&gt;Adaptive Reuse &amp;amp; Creative Misuse&lt;/em&gt;. Drawing from our collective experiences, histories, and methodologies, our goal for the micro-residency to investigate how notions of digital &lt;a class=&quot;internal-link&quot; href=&quot;/infrastructure&quot;&gt;infrastructure&lt;/a&gt; can be reused, reinterpreted, and reconfigured, to realize a kind of &lt;a class=&quot;internal-link&quot; href=&quot;/public-space&quot;&gt;public space&lt;/a&gt;. Our approach to this theme will be composed of a few, very preliminary, subjects that will ground the residency: the situated histories of digital infrastructure, the implications of protocols for &lt;a class=&quot;internal-link&quot; href=&quot;/publishing&quot;&gt;publishing&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;a class=&quot;internal-link&quot; href=&quot;/hypertext&quot;&gt;Hypertext&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a class=&quot;internal-link&quot; href=&quot;/rss&quot;&gt;RSS&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a class=&quot;internal-link&quot; href=&quot;/peer-to-peer&quot;&gt;Peer-to-peer&lt;/a&gt;) in defining public spaces, and the possibilities of cooperative approaches to maintenance and repair. Our intent is to make the process of this investigation &lt;a class=&quot;internal-link&quot; href=&quot;/public-space&quot;&gt;public&lt;/a&gt; through online tools mapping our thinking about the theme (Open channels in Are.na as one example) and cultivating a &lt;a class=&quot;internal-link&quot; href=&quot;/digital-public-garden&quot;&gt;Digital Public Garden&lt;/a&gt; as part of Hypha’s contributions to the initiative (a &lt;a class=&quot;internal-link&quot; href=&quot;/rss&quot;&gt;resyndicatable&lt;/a&gt; adaptive online notebook). The outputs from the &lt;a class=&quot;internal-link&quot; href=&quot;/bentway&quot;&gt;micro-residency&lt;/a&gt; will be a written contribution to the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.are.na/from-later/field-guide-to-the-digital-real&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Field Guide to the Digital Real&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and a micro-website containing the synthesis of our investigations and our evolving practice. The outputs will be textual and visual, and draw from our collaborative practices as a cooperative. They will explore ways to represent relationships with existing and emergent technologies within our communities. Through our micro-residency we will capture a poetic interpretation of the theme and provide prompts for institutions in the city on how they could reconfigure technology to create radically creative platforms.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">[[Hypha]]’s practice is situated across many topics that are present in the theme of Adaptive Reuse &amp;amp; Creative Misuse. Drawing from our collective experiences, histories, and methodologies, our goal for the micro-residency to investigate how notions of digital [[infrastructure]] can be reused, reinterpreted, and reconfigured, to realize a kind of [[public space]]. Our approach to this theme will be composed of a few, very preliminary, subjects that will ground the residency: the situated histories of digital infrastructure, the implications of protocols for [[publishing]] ([[Hypertext]], [[RSS]], [[Peer-to-peer]]) in defining public spaces, and the possibilities of cooperative approaches to maintenance and repair. Our intent is to make the process of this investigation [[public space public]] through online tools mapping our thinking about the theme (Open channels in Are.na as one example) and cultivating a [[Digital Public Garden]] as part of Hypha’s contributions to the initiative (a [[RSS resyndicatable]] adaptive online notebook). The outputs from the [[bentway micro-residency]] will be a written contribution to the Field Guide to the Digital Real and a micro-website containing the synthesis of our investigations and our evolving practice. The outputs will be textual and visual, and draw from our collaborative practices as a cooperative. They will explore ways to represent relationships with existing and emergent technologies within our communities. Through our micro-residency we will capture a poetic interpretation of the theme and provide prompts for institutions in the city on how they could reconfigure technology to create radically creative platforms.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">RSS</title><link href="/rss" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="RSS" /><published>2021-04-03T22:32:28+00:00</published><updated>2021-04-03T22:32:00+00:00</updated><id>/rss</id><content type="html" xml:base="/rss">&lt;p&gt;RSS (RDF Site Summary or Really Simple Syndication) is a web feed that allows users and applications to access updates to websites in a standardized, computer-readable format. These feeds can, for example, allow a user to keep track of many different websites in a single news aggregator. The news aggregator will automatically check the RSS feed for new content, allowing the list to be automatically passed from website to website or from website to user. This passing of content is called web syndication. Websites usually use RSS feeds to publish frequently updated information, such as blog entries, news headlines, or episodes of audio and video series. RSS is also used to distribute podcasts. An RSS document (called “feed”, “web feed”, or “channel”) includes full or summarized text, and metadata, like &lt;a class=&quot;internal-link&quot; href=&quot;/publishing&quot;&gt;publishing&lt;/a&gt; date and author’s name.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/RSS&quot;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/RSS&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">RSS (RDF Site Summary or Really Simple Syndication) is a web feed that allows users and applications to access updates to websites in a standardized, computer-readable format. These feeds can, for example, allow a user to keep track of many different websites in a single news aggregator. The news aggregator will automatically check the RSS feed for new content, allowing the list to be automatically passed from website to website or from website to user. This passing of content is called web syndication. Websites usually use RSS feeds to publish frequently updated information, such as blog entries, news headlines, or episodes of audio and video series. RSS is also used to distribute podcasts. An RSS document (called “feed”, “web feed”, or “channel”) includes full or summarized text, and metadata, like [[publishing]] date and author’s name. https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/RSS</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Publishing</title><link href="/publishing" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Publishing" /><published>2021-04-03T22:32:28+00:00</published><updated>2021-04-03T22:32:00+00:00</updated><id>/publishing</id><content type="html" xml:base="/publishing"></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Public Space</title><link href="/public-space" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Public Space" /><published>2021-04-03T22:32:28+00:00</published><updated>2021-04-03T22:32:00+00:00</updated><id>/public-space</id><content type="html" xml:base="/public-space">&lt;p&gt;TBD&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">TBD</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Protocol</title><link href="/protocol" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Protocol" /><published>2021-04-03T22:32:28+00:00</published><updated>2021-04-03T22:32:00+00:00</updated><id>/protocol</id><content type="html" xml:base="/protocol">&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;A communication protocol is a system of rules that allows two or more entities of a communications system to transmit information via any kind of variation of a physical quantity. The protocol defines the rules, syntax, semantics and synchronization of communication and possible error recovery methods. Protocols may be implemented by hardware, software, or a combination of both.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Communication_protocol&quot;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Communication_protocol&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">A communication protocol is a system of rules that allows two or more entities of a communications system to transmit information via any kind of variation of a physical quantity. The protocol defines the rules, syntax, semantics and synchronization of communication and possible error recovery methods. Protocols may be implemented by hardware, software, or a combination of both. https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Communication_protocol</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">peer-to-peer</title><link href="/peer-to-peer" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="peer-to-peer" /><published>2021-04-03T22:32:28+00:00</published><updated>2021-04-03T22:32:00+00:00</updated><id>/peer-to-peer</id><content type="html" xml:base="/peer-to-peer">&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;internal-link&quot; href=&quot;/hypercore&quot;&gt;Hypercore&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;internal-link&quot; href=&quot;/ipfs&quot;&gt;IPFS&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;TBD&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">[[Hypercore]] [[IPFS]] TBD</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">IPFS</title><link href="/ipfs" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="IPFS" /><published>2021-04-03T22:32:28+00:00</published><updated>2021-04-03T22:32:00+00:00</updated><id>/ipfs</id><content type="html" xml:base="/ipfs">&lt;p&gt;The InterPlanetary File System (IPFS) is a &lt;a class=&quot;internal-link&quot; href=&quot;/protocol&quot;&gt;protocol&lt;/a&gt; and peer-to-peer network for storing and sharing data in a distributed file system. IPFS uses content-addressing to uniquely identify each file in a global namespace connecting all computing devices.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/InterPlanetary_File_System&quot;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/InterPlanetary_File_System&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">The InterPlanetary File System (IPFS) is a [[protocol]] and peer-to-peer network for storing and sharing data in a distributed file system. IPFS uses content-addressing to uniquely identify each file in a global namespace connecting all computing devices. https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/InterPlanetary_File_System</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Initial Seeds</title><link href="/initial-seeds" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Initial Seeds" /><published>2021-04-03T22:32:28+00:00</published><updated>2021-04-03T22:32:00+00:00</updated><id>/initial-seeds</id><content type="html" xml:base="/initial-seeds">&lt;p&gt;Set of areas that guide our reveries?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The history of &lt;a class=&quot;internal-link&quot; href=&quot;/hypertext-transfer-protocol&quot;&gt;hypertext&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a class=&quot;internal-link&quot; href=&quot;/rss&quot;&gt;rss&lt;/a&gt;+adjacent protocols and standards.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The act of &lt;a class=&quot;internal-link&quot; href=&quot;/publishing&quot;&gt;publishing&lt;/a&gt; as “making something public” → publicness → hybrid &lt;a class=&quot;internal-link&quot; href=&quot;/public-space&quot;&gt;public space&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The possibilities for &lt;em&gt;the infrastructural&lt;/em&gt; (maintenance/repair) to draw from the past to rethink the present through co-operative approaches.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;Publish from RSS to arena?
RSS to twitter? The gram? 
Use DPress to get it on SSB?
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;What if… we travel back in time and blow up BGP? Would Xanadu be realized? Would actual plural internetworking have persisted?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Publishing → making things public&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;» COMMISSIONING BODIES «&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;br /&gt;
Economy as a form a expression&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Antagonizing the separation of frontend/backend&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Set of areas that guide our reveries? The history of [[hypertext transfer protocol hypertext]], [[rss]]+adjacent protocols and standards. The act of [[publishing]] as “making something public” → publicness → hybrid [[public space]]. The possibilities for the infrastructural (maintenance/repair) to draw from the past to rethink the present through co-operative approaches.</summary></entry></feed>